<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Andrew is a Product Designer and Entrepreneur. My expertise is compassed from my years of experience in software development, Analytics and Technical Team Management.</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Team Leadership Roles</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;From Dr. Meredith Belbins research on Team Leadership roles based on Action-Oriented, Thought Oriented and People-Oriented Team structures, He, Belbin defines a ‘team role’ as “a tendency to behave, contribute and interrelate with others in a particular way”. Therefore, by analysing how leadership is effected in teams you can categorise team leaders into the following.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/team-leadership-roles</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/team-leadership-roles</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Objective Driven Team Structure</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Team members are often chosen for the wrong reasons: for example, they are often chosen because they have an interest in the project, because their wage is affordable, or most often simply because they are available. They are not chosen with Result Actualization based on Project objectives in mind. This brings to attention the need for developing a team formation structure with a focus on optimal output. &lt;strong&gt;Structuring teams for optimal output are at the core of the Result Driven Team Methodology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/result-oriented-teams</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/result-oriented-teams</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Why do teams fail ?</title>
        
          <description>Most team problems arise from a lack in MOI, which stands for Motivation, Organization and Information, evidence from retrogressive teams prove that the lack of initial motivation and drive, or a clear sense of hierachy</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/why-teams-fail</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/why-teams-fail</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Nature, the Mother of Tech</title>
        
          <description>Birds could fly before the Wright brothers created the plane, Neural networks existed within the deep roots of trees that allow them to share nutrients and communicate</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/nature-mother-of-tech</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/nature-mother-of-tech</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Your Manager wants you to succeed</title>
        
          <description>We are wired to work, it's our nature, to glorify God as we cultivate blessing from the created order and contribute value to others through the labor of our minds, hearts, and hands.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/manager-wants-your-success</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/manager-wants-your-success</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Nigeria Decides 2019</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 23rd of February Nigerians will decide a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2019_Nigerian_general_election&quot;&gt;New President&lt;/a&gt;. Who we expect will lead us to the promise land&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/nigerian-elections-update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/nigerian-elections-update</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Traditions and Cultures we learnt from our Forefathers</title>
        
          <description>While growing up in the village, I observed that when elders gather, they always “litter” a portion of wine on the ground</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/fetishes-our-forefathers-practiced</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/fetishes-our-forefathers-practiced</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Defining who we are</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;We work every day, somehow it seems like most of us were wired this way, some say the hustle is real or the struggle is, you can define yours anyway. If it isn't toiling with engines and machines, making glue stick, talking your way into people's heart or speeding across geographical boundaries, for some it's transversing needle and thread across the epidermis, writing our way into the thought patterns of industries, fields, and organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/humans-and-work</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/humans-and-work</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>7 Valuable guides for Living</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently going through my document archive and found some age long advise I had given myself, which I consider very valuable advise to anyone, so here I am sharing it with you and I hope it turns out to be very useful to you too. These are my 7 valuable guides for living&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/valuable-guides-for-living</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/valuable-guides-for-living</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>String Reversal in Javascript</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In this javascript algorithm, I would be sharing with us different methods to reverse a string in javascript.
This is a common exercise in coding interviews, entry level algorithm challenges, though implementation in various languages may be different we would be looking at how to reverse a string in javascript, hope this helps you.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/algorithms-js-string-reversal</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/algorithms-js-string-reversal</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Boiled Plaintain</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Not so early this morning I had breakfast, not the usual kind but before we get to that let’s talk about the period before this.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/boiled-plantain</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/boiled-plantain</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Deadlines or Lifeline ?</title>
        
          <description>As Project Managers or startup founders you many have come to a situation where you gave a developer a job to do for you with an ETA only to be dissapointed with</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/deadline-vs-lifeline</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/deadline-vs-lifeline</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>What can a course in programming to do you ?</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So you may be wondering what benefits you get from learning how to code, apart from the obvious benefits, learning how to code can help you&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/what-can-programming-do-for-me</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/what-can-programming-do-for-me</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>After Software Development what next ?</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across an acquaintaince who had about 20 years of experience in the software development field, and was wondering what next he should do at this point in his career and life, though I didnt have the opportunity to share my answers to him, at the top of my head, these were my thoughts&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/after-software-development-what-next</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/after-software-development-what-next</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Palindrome in Javascript</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In this javascript algorithm exercise, I would be sharing how to write a palindrome algorithm in javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/algorithms-js-palindrome</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/algorithms-js-palindrome</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Lessons learned from building for startups</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Although we’d like to develop products and services iteratively, the truth is organisations think in terms of strict deadlines – and budgets. We product owners need to think about how we manage this.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/lessons-learned-from-startups</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/lessons-learned-from-startups</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Managing Christmas Depression</title>
        
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Christmas is almost a week away and like they say, depression is tough at the best of times. Perhaps it’s the best of times as the holiday/season of Christmas is when it’s especially tough.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/christmas-depression</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/christmas-depression</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Dive straight to code or wireframe</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I was chatting with someone recently who’s building their first website for a paying client. He’s doing extremely well, grappling with setting up hosting, domain names, WIX, Wordpress, CMS templates, Twig &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; HTML and CSS. That’s a lot to simply learn. Producing something that’s someone’s willing to pay for while you learn is doubly difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/dive-to-code-or-wireframe</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/dive-to-code-or-wireframe</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>How God Coded the High Priest Order</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;If Prayer had version control, we can argue that the alpha edition were experienced in the old testament, all protocols went through the high priest into the inner chamber who them &lt;code&gt;dispatched(prayer.actions)&lt;/code&gt; through &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;api.heaven&lt;/a&gt;. In this model prayer was a single threaded protocol. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/god-code-high-priest-order</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/god-code-high-priest-order</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Giving without expectation</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Why is it easy for people to give when they have or most likely give with an expectation to receive, this is very popular within the African continent especially in Nigeria, that is why folks can invest in schemes like zarfund, mmm, ultimatecycle and the rest of them, because they have been promised to gain back how much they give with even a lot more profit.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/giving-receiving</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/giving-receiving</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Measuring User experience</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone thinks &lt;em&gt;experience&lt;/em&gt; is important. After all, the argument goes, the ultimate reason for using any service is to experience something, whether that’s a sense of wonder and excitement when you discover something new, enjoyment at some particularly interesting writing or, more prosaically, a sense of relief at paying an overdue bill.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /posts/measuring-experience</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/measuring-experience</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
