<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-17T21:26:32+00:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Andrew Miracle</title><subtitle>Andrew is a Product Designer and Entrepreneur. My expertise is compassed from my years of experience in software development, Analytics and Technical Team Management.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Objective Driven Team Structure</title><link href="/posts/result-oriented-teams" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Objective Driven Team Structure" /><published>2019-11-17T21:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-17T21:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/result-oriented-teams</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/result-oriented-teams">&lt;p&gt;Team members are often chosen for the wrong reasons: for example, they are often chosen because they have an interest in the project, because their wage is affordable, or most often simply because they are available. They are not chosen with objective actualization in mind. This brings to attention the need for developing a team formation structure that is focused on optimal output. &lt;strong&gt;Structuring teams for optimal output are at the core of the Result Driven Team Methodology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adopting from the OKR Playbook (Objectives and Key Results), a popular management strategy for goal setting within organizations driven by connecting companies, teams and personal goals to measurable results while having all team members and leaders work together in one, unified direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-objective-driven-team-structures&quot;&gt;What are Objective Driven Team Structures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first consideration in organizing a team is to determine the team’s broad objective. Here are the broad objectives according to Larson and LaFasto&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Problem resolution
• Creativity
• Tactical execution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve established the broad objective, you choose a team structure that matches it. Larson and LaFasto define three general team structures for effective, high-performance team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes more than just a group of people who happen to work together to constitute a team. In thek book The Wisdom of Teams, Katzenbach and Smith (1993) define a team as “a small number of people with complementary skills who are committed to a common purpose, performance goals, and approach for which they hold themselves mutually accountable.” Teamwork can come into play on software projects on any number of spescific tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;objective-driven-teams-are-result-driven-teams-and-have-essential-characteristics&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective driven teams are result driven teams and have essential characteristics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Steve’s (Rapid Development)[www.AMAZON_LINK.com], there are four essential characteristics of a results-driven team structure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roles must be clear, and everyone must be accountable for their work at all times. Accountability is critical to effective decision making and to rapid execution after the decisions have been made.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The team must have an effective communication system that supports the free flow of information among team members. Communication must flow freely both from and to the team’s management.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The team must have some means of monitoring individual performance and providing feedback. The team should know whom to reward, who needs  individual development, and who can assume more responsibilities in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decisions must be made based on facts rather than on subjective opinions whenever possible. The team needs to be sure that the facts are interpreted without biases that undercut the functioning of the team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a strong desire to contribute among team members of Objective Driven teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team members are committed to the team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is an indentifiable level of inter-dependence among team members - team members learn to rely on each other to accomplish certain tasks and goals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A sense of Autonomy among team members, with little to no interference, according to research, when there is a problem instead of managers taking it upon themselves to punish or solve these issues, they should rather walk by the side of the teams to point them in the right direction for how to go about their blocks or productivity conflict&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strong sense of Empowerment among team members, Team members feel like they have the power to use up the resources and privileges available to them for the benefit of the team, Learning from the rework project, Google gives their engineers access to their codebase which is worth an incredible wealth of knowledge for new engineers to explore and make input into the processes at the heart of the organization.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High level of enjoyment, in Objective Driven teams, due to the massive gains of accomplished goals and milestones, team members tend to take happiness seriously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;achieving-objective-driven-team-structures&quot;&gt;Achieving Objective Driven Team Structures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manage Teams as Teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In team selection, ensure there is a blend of technical, business, management and inter-personal skills, of course this would vary across various disciplines and not only apply to the world or business or startups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure that team members obtain specific soft skills, or collaboration skills required to work effectively with others, if communications is aligned with slack or issues are traiged with github, team leads and managers should ensure that all team members are fully acquainted with the resource and knowledge to use these tools and frameworks in order to streamline communication and collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-call-for-the-need-for-result-driven-team-structures-so-what-are-these-result-driven-teams-are-driven-by-a-common-goal-and-vision-and-are-invested-in-the-same-amount-of-work-and-tide-so-they-work-on-how-to-make-things&quot;&gt;This call for the need for result driven team structures, so what are these, result driven teams are driven by a common goal and vision and are invested in the same amount of work and tide, so they work on how to make things.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, a lot of reading can try to point you to the right direction as to how to achieve this goals, I decided to highlight these characteristics so that you as team members can identify the state of your team and take action.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Team members are often chosen for the wrong reasons: for example, they are often chosen because they have an interest in the project, because their wage is affordable, or most often simply because they are available. They are not chosen with objective actualization in mind. This brings to attention the need for developing a team formation structure that is focused on optimal output. Structuring teams for optimal output are at the core of the Result Driven Team Methodology</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why do teams fail ?</title><link href="/posts/why-teams-fail" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why do teams fail ?" /><published>2019-11-15T21:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-15T21:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/why-teams-fail</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/why-teams-fail">&lt;p&gt;Most team problems are associated with an inefficiency in MOI, which stands for Motivation, Organization and Information, evidence from regressive teams prove that the lack of initial motivation and drive, or a clear sense of hierachy, structure and rules of engagement in organizations and even the lack of resource to consume in order to understand how to accomplish goals breaks down a majority of teams formed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see this illustrated in our everyday life from our favorite sports, bands, groups in a varying array, a major number of successful teams in the face of these constraints have two things in common, these teams have a SWAT and a Supporter as part of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term SWAT adopted from from Steve McConell’s work is an acronym for &lt;em&gt;Skilled With Advanced Tools&lt;/em&gt;, this refers to a specific individual that possess domain specific knowlege, or deep technical skills in an platform, area, framework or language, a SWAT is a master in his field and understands all the code and nuances of his subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas we adapt the Supporter role from Dr. Meredith Belbins research on Team Leadership roles based on Action Oriented, Thought Oriented and People Oriented Team structures, He explains that a supporter builds on team members’ strengths and underpins their
shortcomings. Provides emotional leadership and fosters team spirit. Improves communications among team members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-references-here-are-a-quick-rundown-of-all-leadership-roles-from-belbins-work&quot;&gt;For References here are a quick rundown of all Leadership Roles from Belbin’s work&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Driver: controls team direction at a. detailed, tactical level. Defines things, steers and shapes group discussions and activities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coordinator: controls team direction at the highest, strategic level. Moves the problem-solving forward by recognizing strengths and weaknesses and making the best use of human and other resources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Originator: provides leadership in ideas, innovating and inventing ideas and strategies, especially on major issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monitor: analyzes problems from a practical point of view and evaluates ideas and suggestions so that the team can make balanced decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Implementer: converts concepts and plans into work procedures and carries out group plans efficiently and as agreed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investigator—Explores and reports on ideas, developments, and resources outside the group. Creates external contacts that may be useful to the group.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finisher—Ensures that all necessary work is completed in all details. Seeks work that needs greater than average attention to detail, and maintains the group’s focus and sense of urgency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the years, Dr. Belbin’s research has immersed into team structures which you might find interesting to dig further into (Team roles Belbin)[https://www.belbin.com/about/belbin-team-roles/]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently as much as we may want to pose that most teams fail, we must understand that failure is a state of the mind, from the IBM Design Playbook, as Multidisciplinary independent teams focused on a Hill, it is important to fail fast, regarding failure as a learning opportunity, in order words, fail fast and iterate quickly. As Thato Rammoko quotes &lt;strong&gt;Humans never fail, We only run out of Time, Scope or Capacity&lt;/strong&gt; The TSC arguement is a topic for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-do-teams-fail-&quot;&gt;Why do Teams Fail ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Autonomy, this can be related to the Diverse Talented team in the IBM Design Thinking Course, where teams should be bound by a common goal and objective, not by processes, identifying&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MOI, Motivation, Objective, I***&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supporter, every team needs a supporter, a common arguement within this brings about the need for gender balance among teams, because in over 50% of the time, females are more empathic than their male fellow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not deciding on a conflict resolution framework, most people try to shy away from conflict so they don’t hurt their team mates feelings, establishing a line of action in case of conflict and opening up communication can save a team from breaking up during conflicts. acccording to Tukman’s law[link], this stage commonly referred to as the storming stage is completely inevitable and would eventually come, what is best is for the team to get past this cycle. The truth is that at the point of any major breakthrough, the most successful team had to navigate past their storm stage to get to where they are today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;indicators-a-dysfunctional-team&quot;&gt;Indicators a Dysfunctional Team&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cohesiveness of a group depends on the total field of forces that act on that group. Taking to account the models that direct the formation of teams, from (Corporate Skunkworks team )[https://fortune.com/2017/06/15/corporate-skunkworks-innovation-startups-facebook-oracle-walmart/], Feature Teams, SWAT (Special Weapons And Tactics) Teams, Feature Teams, being able to idenity a point of instability within the team can help towards streamlining objectives and goals amongst members even better, Signs that a team isn’t functioning well are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rigidity among roles being played.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack of commitment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack of Trust and Mutual confidence, Larson has stated that Trust hangs on Honesty, Opennes, Consistency and Respect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This are a few indicators among others, just as team structures are chosen for the wrong reasons, team members are often chosen for the wrong reasons: for example, they are often chosen because they have an interest in the project, because their wage is affordable, or most
often simply because they are available. They are not chosen with objective actualization in mind. This brings to attention the need for developing a team formation structure that is focused on optimal output. &lt;strong&gt;Structuring teams for optimal output are at the core of the Result Driven Team Methodology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-result-driven-team-structures&quot;&gt;What are Result Driven Team Structures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first consideration in organizing a team is to determine the team’s broad objective. Here are the broad objectives according to Larson and LaFasto&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Problem resolution
• Creativity
• Tactical execution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve established the broad objective, you choose a team structure that matches it. Larson and LaFasto define three general team structures for effective, high-performance team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes more than just a group of people who happen to work together to constitute a team. In thek book The Wisdom of Teams, Katzenbach and Smith (1993) define a team as “a small number of people with complementary skills who are committed to a common purpose, performance goals, and approach for which they hold themselves mutually accountable.” Teamwork can come into play on software projects on any number of spescific tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;essential-characteristics-of-result-driven-teams&quot;&gt;Essential Characteristics of Result Driven Teams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Steve’s (Rapid Development)[www.AMAZON_LINK.com], there are four essential characteristics of a results-driven team structure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roles must be clear, and everyone must be accountable for their work at all times. Accountability is critical to effective decision making and to rapid execution after the decisions have been made.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The team must have an effective communication system that supports the free flow of information among team members. Communication must flow freely both from and to the team’s management.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The team must have some means of monitoring individual performance and providing feedback. The team should know whom to reward, who needs  individual development, and who can assume more responsibilities in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decisions must be made based on facts rather than on subjective opinions whenever possible. The team needs to be sure that the facts are interpreted without biases that undercut the functioning of the team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a strong desire to contribute among team members of Result Driven teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team members are committed to the team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is an indentifiable level of inter-dependence among team members - team members learn to rely on each other to accomplish certain tasks and goals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A sense of Autonomy among team members, with little to no interference, according to research, when there is a problem instead of managers taking it upon themselves to punish or solve these issues, they should rather walk by the side of the teams to point them in the right direction for how to go about their blocks or productivity conflict&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strong sense of Empowerment among team members, Team members feel like they have the power to use up the resources and privileges available to them for the benefit of the team, Learning from the rework project, Google gives their engineers access to their codebase which is worth an incredible wealth of knowledge for new engineers to explore and make input into the processes at the heart of the organization.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High level of enjoyment, in Result Driven teams, due to the massive gains of accomplished goals and milestones, team members tend to take happiness seriously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;achieving-result-driven-team-structures&quot;&gt;Achieving Result Driven Team Structures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manage Teams as Teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In team selection, ensure there is a blend of technical, business, management and inter-personal skills, of course this would vary across various disciplines and not only apply to the world or business or startups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure that team members obtain specific soft skills, or collaboration skills required to work effectively with others, if communications is aligned with slack or issues are traiged with github, team leads and managers should ensure that all team members are fully acquainted with the resource and knowledge to use these tools and frameworks in order to streamline communication and collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-call-for-the-need-for-result-driven-team-structures-so-what-are-these-result-driven-teams-are-driven-by-a-common-goal-and-vision-and-are-invested-in-the-same-amount-of-work-and-tide-so-they-work-on-how-to-make-things&quot;&gt;This call for the need for result driven team structures, so what are these, result driven teams are driven by a common goal and vision and are invested in the same amount of work and tide, so they work on how to make things.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, a lot of reading can try to point you to the right direction as to how to achieve this goals, I decided to highlight these characteristics so that you as team members can identify the state of your team and take action.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">every successful team needs two set of individuals, a SWAT and a supporter according to the M****** rule of leadership</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nature, the Mother of Tech</title><link href="/posts/biology-mother-of-tech" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nature, the Mother of Tech" /><published>2019-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/biology-mother-of-tech</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/biology-mother-of-tech">&lt;p&gt;Birds could fly before the wright brothers created the plane, possible to argue is the statement that they didn’t create the plane, according to their &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wright_brothers_patent_war&quot;&gt;patent&lt;/a&gt;, which stirred controversy for over a decade and even after their death. &lt;em&gt;The Wright brothers claimed to have created an aeronautical flying control system&lt;/em&gt; which proves that we were only trying to understand what nature had already designed, flight, which eagles and birds of all kinds have been utilizing, although the Wright brothers weren’t the only ones working on the invention of &lt;strong&gt;flight&lt;/strong&gt; systems during their time, why theirs succeded was because other inventors were more focused on creating highly efficient flight engines, without considering the conditions of the pilots who would control the plane, thus the Wright brothers were able to breakthrough because they designed from the Pilot’s perspective, doing so would enable them conduct further user experiments to improve flight control and efficiency, citing a case where nature is one step ahead of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nature and biology has already perfected theories which we today seek for in science and technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider machine learning and Neural networks, and How Trees already have a deep link of communication. Did you know that when cut the grass in your fields or pluck a freshly grown rose flower, the scent you perceive with your nose, as perfume from the flowers, or greens from the grass is actually a distress call to nature made my the flowers for ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning and Deep learning leverages the concept of neural networks and &lt;em&gt;decision trees&lt;/em&gt; in order to build highly complicated recommendation and learning systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trees today has VOCS and Mi***** which allow them to shutdown or call for help, If you love foraging grasses and picnics you will realize that when you seat on the grass for so long, its only a matter of time before unfriendly insects begin to disturb your peace, because their neighbouring grasses have called for their help to push you human away from sitting down on them and suffocating them of air. piece of advise change your location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nature loves when tech is working in its favour, that’s why we find Cannabis and Agritech startups receiving the best in support they need. &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.crunchbase.com/news/twiga-foods-lands-over-30m-nairobis-largest-known-financing-round-of-the-year/&quot;&gt;Twiga Food lands over $30Million&lt;/a&gt; in Financing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neural networks existed within the deep roots of trees that allow them to share nutrients and communicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trees have their neural networks : The applications of deep learning are growing so vast that it has made a great headway into areas requiring heavy computing. And, the elements that make up DL models — artificial neural networks (ANN) — can be said to be the driving force behind the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1711.09784.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; Distilling a Neural Network Into a Soft Decision Tree, Hinton and Prosst tell why decision trees are preferred to elucidate neural nets. “Unlike the hidden units in a neural net, a typical node at the lower levels of a decision tree is only used by a very small fraction of the training data so the lower parts of the decision tree tend to overfit unless the size of the training set is exponentially large compared with the depth of the tree.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hinton and Frosst use the neural network itself to train on a decision tree. If large amounts of data are encountered, poor statistical efficiency observed in decision trees is nullified by neural nets. An important point here, ‘soft decision trees’ are considered to train the neural net. Soft decision trees mean children nodes (also known as the leaf or terminal node if it ends here) in a decision tree are assigned a certain probability. Also, all leaves contribute equally to the final decision in the tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chameleons can change their color according to their environment in order to blend in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bug and error reporting, Garbage collection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain today is trying to relive the same concepts of publicly immutable ledger where all transactions are recorded and known among all parties, today we relive that concepts already in childbirth, whereas we have smart contracts where two conditions meet for a transaction to be recorded on the ledger, in childbirth we have two more so dumb contract where consent is given by two parties and there is a constantly estimated time to arrival &lt;strong&gt;~9months&lt;/strong&gt; with which a transaction can be recorded as complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blockchain-and-childbirth&quot;&gt;Blockchain and Childbirth&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain can be used to prove ownership when procuring or disposing of an asset. It can also help to track the history of an assets and related maintenance activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Blockchain is a type of diary or spreadsheet containing information about transactions. Each transaction generates a hash. … If a transaction is approved by a majority of the nodes then it is written into a block. Each block refers to the previous block and together make the Blockchain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI exists because of Natural Intelligence (Today Chams can auto adapt- case study)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neural Networks existed within Trees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blockchain Networks are trying to do what DNA’s have been doing long time ago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what modern invention are we looking in tech today that we cannot link to nature.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><category term="code" /><summary type="html">Birds could fly before the Wright brothers created the plane, Neural networks existed within the deep roots of trees that allow them to share nutrients and communicate</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Your Manager wants you to succeed</title><link href="/posts/manager-wants-your-success" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Your Manager wants you to succeed" /><published>2019-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/manager-wants-your-success</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/manager-wants-your-success">&lt;p&gt;We are wired to work, it’s our nature, to glorify God as we cultivate blessing from the created order and contribute value to others through the labor of our minds, hearts, and hands. For most of us this work greets us each Monday morning with a myriad of thorns and thistles. Sometimes we may struggle with our work or with our Managers, Head of Departments, Leaders etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Your manager wants you to succeed that's the hard truth&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the amount of pressure and expectation in our modern workplaces today, it could be hard to agree that your manager wants you to succeed. Sometimes they may not have the best way of showing it, however, you completing a task helps the company hit some KPI, meet their target and that means results, the type that can help the company’s decision making process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for someone who finds themselves under this form of management or leadership its very important that you should be able to :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-your-work-without-drama&quot;&gt;Do your work without drama&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No body likes to shout or talk too much, if you are given a task, get head on with it and clear it off with less drama and clutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;avoid-giving-excuses&quot;&gt;Avoid giving excuses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This accompanies the drama rule, don’t be or act like an incompetent or relegate yourself to the company liability list, don’t be a farm of excuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ask-questions-when-confused&quot;&gt;Ask questions when confused&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not the stupid ones of course, It is however beneficial to be able to communicate your confusion in a clear and concise manner, upper management staff usually don’t have a lot of time on their hands, so these fellows tend to appreciate concise and straight to the point approaches. It also goes to say that, If you’re having difficulties let them know before hand, however, this is not a license to be giving excuses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remember-the-pareto-principle&quot;&gt;Remember the Pareto Principle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You remember the 80/20 rule, yeah of course, this time around in the workplace you want to be among the 20% that’s responsible for 80% of the companies output, these output means result that’s helping your organization hit a target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More importantly be good at what you do. The truth is that your success is theirs too.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am aware that there could be edge cases where you could be dealing with a difficult manager or boss, if you do find yourself in such situation here’s a simple prayer, where I always find encouragement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lord Jesus, you know I am having a hard time loving that person at work. Their insensitive words and actions are so wounding and hurtful. I really want to avoid them and at times I want to retaliate against them. Lord, guard my heart from bitterness and resentment. Empower me to look for ways to bless them, to overcome evil with good, and to seek their flourishing. (Romans 12:17–19)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html">We are wired to work, it's our nature, to glorify God as we cultivate blessing from the created order and contribute value to others through the labor of our minds, hearts, and hands.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nigeria Decides 2019</title><link href="/posts/nigerian-elections-update" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nigeria Decides 2019" /><published>2019-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/nigerian-elections-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/nigerian-elections-update">&lt;p&gt;On the 23rd of February Nigerians will decide a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2019_Nigerian_general_election&quot;&gt;New President&lt;/a&gt;. Who we expect will lead us to the promise land&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly the reason I am here is that I and a few friends have put together &lt;a href=&quot;https://ngdecides.tecmie.com&quot;&gt;Nigeria Election&lt;/a&gt;, an RSS source feed for results from the Nigerian Elections held in 2019, hopefully in an easy to &lt;strong&gt;navigate, search and review manner&lt;/strong&gt;, more importantly this source feeds a Facebook/Messenger chatbot that you can subscribe to receive results updates on every state in real time from their collation centers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;svg viewBox=&quot;0 0 800 600&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; xml:space=&quot;preserve&quot;&gt;&lt;g font-family=&quot;Arial&quot; font-size=&quot;11px&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; stroke-linecap=&quot;square&quot;&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b19992&quot; x=&quot;0&quot; y=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b19992&quot; fill=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; /&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;b19993&quot; stroke-linecap=&quot;butt&quot; d=&quot;M270.5,105.5 A195,195 0 0 1 270.66,105.5 L270.5,300.5 L270.5,105.5 Z&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b19993&quot; fill=&quot;#FF6666&quot; stroke=&quot;#FF6666&quot; /&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;b19994&quot; stroke-linecap=&quot;butt&quot; d=&quot;M269.735,105.502 A195,195 0 0 1 270.5,105.5 L270.5,300.5 L269.735,105.502 Z&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b19994&quot; fill=&quot;#CCFFFF&quot; stroke=&quot;#CCFFFF&quot; /&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;b19995&quot; stroke-linecap=&quot;butt&quot; d=&quot;M270.66,105.5 A195,195 0 0 1 271.383,105.502 L270.5,300.5 L270.66,105.5 Z&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b19995&quot; fill=&quot;#80FF80&quot; stroke=&quot;#80FF80&quot; /&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;b19996&quot; stroke-linecap=&quot;butt&quot; d=&quot;M271.383,105.502 A195,195 0 0 1 271.611,105.503 L270.5,300.5 L271.383,105.502 Z&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b19996&quot; fill=&quot;#6666FF&quot; stroke=&quot;#6666FF&quot; /&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;b19997&quot; stroke-linecap=&quot;butt&quot; d=&quot;M263.872,495.387 A195,195 0 0 1 269.735,105.502 L270.5,300.5 L263.872,495.387 Z&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b19997&quot; fill=&quot;#FF66FF&quot; stroke=&quot;#FF66FF&quot; /&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;b19998&quot; stroke-linecap=&quot;butt&quot; d=&quot;M271.611,105.503 A195,195 0 1 1 263.872,495.387 L270.5,300.5 L271.611,105.503 Z&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b19998&quot; fill=&quot;#FFFF80&quot; stroke=&quot;#FFFF80&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b19999&quot; x1=&quot;270.5&quot; y1=&quot;105.5&quot; x2=&quot;270.5&quot; y2=&quot;104.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b19999&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20000&quot; x1=&quot;270.5&quot; y1=&quot;104.5&quot; x2=&quot;461.5&quot; y2=&quot;104.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20000&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20001&quot; x1=&quot;461.5&quot; y1=&quot;104.5&quot; x2=&quot;479.5&quot; y2=&quot;86.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20001&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20002&quot; x1=&quot;479.5&quot; y1=&quot;86.5&quot; x2=&quot;480.5&quot; y2=&quot;86.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20002&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b20003&quot; x=&quot;480.5&quot; y=&quot;77.5&quot; width=&quot;13&quot; height=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20003&quot; fill=&quot;#FF6666&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20004&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:13px;&quot; x=&quot;484&quot; y=&quot;91&quot;&gt;1&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20004&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20005&quot; x1=&quot;271.5&quot; y1=&quot;105.5&quot; x2=&quot;271.5&quot; y2=&quot;104.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20005&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20006&quot; x1=&quot;271.5&quot; y1=&quot;104.5&quot; x2=&quot;479.5&quot; y2=&quot;104.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20006&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20007&quot; x1=&quot;479.5&quot; y1=&quot;104.5&quot; x2=&quot;480.5&quot; y2=&quot;104.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20007&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b20008&quot; x=&quot;480.5&quot; y=&quot;95.5&quot; width=&quot;13&quot; height=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20008&quot; fill=&quot;#80FF80&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20009&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:13px;&quot; x=&quot;484&quot; y=&quot;109&quot;&gt;2&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20009&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20010&quot; x1=&quot;271.5&quot; y1=&quot;105.5&quot; x2=&quot;271.5&quot; y2=&quot;104.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20010&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20011&quot; x1=&quot;271.5&quot; y1=&quot;104.5&quot; x2=&quot;461.5&quot; y2=&quot;104.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20011&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20012&quot; x1=&quot;461.5&quot; y1=&quot;104.5&quot; x2=&quot;479.5&quot; y2=&quot;122.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20012&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20013&quot; x1=&quot;479.5&quot; y1=&quot;122.5&quot; x2=&quot;480.5&quot; y2=&quot;122.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20013&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b20014&quot; x=&quot;480.5&quot; y=&quot;113.5&quot; width=&quot;13&quot; height=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20014&quot; fill=&quot;#6666FF&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20015&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:13px;&quot; x=&quot;484&quot; y=&quot;127&quot;&gt;3&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20015&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20016&quot; x1=&quot;465.5&quot; y1=&quot;304.5&quot; x2=&quot;466.5&quot; y2=&quot;304.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20016&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20017&quot; x1=&quot;466.5&quot; y1=&quot;304.5&quot; x2=&quot;479.5&quot; y2=&quot;304.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20017&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20018&quot; x1=&quot;479.5&quot; y1=&quot;304.5&quot; x2=&quot;480.5&quot; y2=&quot;304.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20018&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b20019&quot; x=&quot;480.5&quot; y=&quot;295.5&quot; width=&quot;13&quot; height=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20019&quot; fill=&quot;#FFFF80&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20020&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:13px;&quot; x=&quot;484&quot; y=&quot;309&quot;&gt;4&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20020&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20021&quot; x1=&quot;75.5&quot; y1=&quot;297.5&quot; x2=&quot;74.5&quot; y2=&quot;297.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20021&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20022&quot; x1=&quot;74.5&quot; y1=&quot;297.5&quot; x2=&quot;60.5&quot; y2=&quot;297.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20022&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20023&quot; x1=&quot;60.5&quot; y1=&quot;297.5&quot; x2=&quot;59.5&quot; y2=&quot;297.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20023&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b20024&quot; x=&quot;46.5&quot; y=&quot;288.5&quot; width=&quot;13&quot; height=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20024&quot; fill=&quot;#FF66FF&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20025&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:13px;&quot; x=&quot;50&quot; y=&quot;302&quot;&gt;5&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20025&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20026&quot; x1=&quot;270.5&quot; y1=&quot;105.5&quot; x2=&quot;270.5&quot; y2=&quot;104.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20026&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20027&quot; x1=&quot;270.5&quot; y1=&quot;104.5&quot; x2=&quot;60.5&quot; y2=&quot;104.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20027&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;line id=&quot;b20028&quot; x1=&quot;60.5&quot; y1=&quot;104.5&quot; x2=&quot;59.5&quot; y2=&quot;104.5&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20028&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b20029&quot; x=&quot;46.5&quot; y=&quot;95.5&quot; width=&quot;13&quot; height=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20029&quot; fill=&quot;#CCFFFF&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20030&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:13px;&quot; x=&quot;50&quot; y=&quot;109&quot;&gt;6&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20030&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b20031&quot; x=&quot;561.5&quot; y=&quot;110.5&quot; width=&quot;9&quot; height=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20031&quot; fill=&quot;#FF6666&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20032&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:13px;&quot; x=&quot;576&quot; y=&quot;120&quot;&gt;1. AAC 75&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20032&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b20033&quot; x=&quot;561.5&quot; y=&quot;133.5&quot; width=&quot;9&quot; height=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20033&quot; fill=&quot;#80FF80&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20034&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:13px;&quot; x=&quot;576&quot; y=&quot;143&quot;&gt;2. ADC 339&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20034&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b20035&quot; x=&quot;561.5&quot; y=&quot;156.5&quot; width=&quot;9&quot; height=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20035&quot; fill=&quot;#6666FF&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20036&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:13px;&quot; x=&quot;576&quot; y=&quot;166&quot;&gt;3. ADP 107&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20036&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b20037&quot; x=&quot;561.5&quot; y=&quot;179.5&quot; width=&quot;9&quot; height=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20037&quot; fill=&quot;#FFFF80&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20038&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:13px;&quot; x=&quot;576&quot; y=&quot;189&quot;&gt;4. APC 289903&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20038&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b20039&quot; x=&quot;561.5&quot; y=&quot;202.5&quot; width=&quot;9&quot; height=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20039&quot; fill=&quot;#FF66FF&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20040&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:13px;&quot; x=&quot;576&quot; y=&quot;212&quot;&gt;5. PDP 283847&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20040&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;rect id=&quot;b20041&quot; x=&quot;561.5&quot; y=&quot;225.5&quot; width=&quot;9&quot; height=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20041&quot; fill=&quot;#CCFFFF&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20042&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:13px;&quot; x=&quot;576&quot; y=&quot;235&quot;&gt;6. SDP 359&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20042&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;text id=&quot;b20043&quot; style=&quot;font-family:'Open Sans Semibold';font-size:17px;&quot; x=&quot;304&quot; y=&quot;24&quot;&gt;Nasarawa State Results&lt;/text&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&quot;#b20043&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot; /&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;flex items-center justify-center pa4 bg-lightest-blue navy&quot;&gt;
  &lt;svg class=&quot;w1&quot; data-icon=&quot;info&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 32 32&quot; style=&quot;fill:currentcolor&quot;&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;info icon&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;path d=&quot;M16 0 A16 16 0 0 1 16 32 A16 16 0 0 1 16 0 M19 15 L13 15 L13 26 L19 26 z M16 6 A3 3 0 0 0 16 12 A3 3 0 0 0 16 6&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
  &lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;lh-title ml3&quot;&gt;You can contribute to this project on Github, hopefully this is useful to someone &lt;a class=&quot;f6 link dim ba ph3 pv2 white&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tecmie/ng-election-feed/&quot;&gt;See on Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="open-source" /><summary type="html">On the 23rd of February Nigerians will decide a New President. Who we expect will lead us to the promise land</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Traditions and Cultures we learnt from our Forefathers</title><link href="/posts/fetishes-our-forefathers-practiced" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Traditions and Cultures we learnt from our Forefathers" /><published>2019-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/fetishes-our-forefathers-practiced</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/fetishes-our-forefathers-practiced">&lt;p&gt;While growing up in the village, I observed that when elders gather, they always “litter” a portion of wine on the ground, making some incantations which include asking dead men to protect them! Of course the ancestors do not wake up and drink the palm wine. But “wasting” that palm wine is extremely important for a lot of reasons, one of which is safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One key thing I observed was that when the wine is poured on the ground, some elders check if ants congregate towards the wine. If ants do come towards the “littered” wine, it means the wine is not poisoned and safe for drinking. However if the wine is poured and ants do not come around, or either run away – That wine may not safe for drinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking a walk through the evening as you would expect on a Sunday through the streets of Lagos, you wouldn’t help but be amused at how young adults and teens pour libations with Star, Gulder, Orijin etc on cemented floors, when technically the packaging has reduced the possibility of poisoning, and African ants are not consumers of chemicalized beers! :D . Traditionally, on safety frameworks, there is no reason for that. But most people imitate without knowing the basis of the pouring. Yes, you can pray with your &lt;strong&gt;'’foreign’‘&lt;/strong&gt; beer without a need to waste any portion of it, now you can say your prayer with knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not imitate the old without full knowledge of the intentions and consequences.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html">While growing up in the village, I observed that when elders gather, they always “litter” a portion of wine on the ground</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Defining who we are</title><link href="/posts/humans-and-work" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Defining who we are" /><published>2019-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/humans-and-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/humans-and-work">&lt;p&gt;We work every day, somehow it seems like most of us were wired this way, some say the hustle is real or the struggle is, you can define yours anyway. If it isn't toiling with engines and machines, making glue stick, talking your way into people's heart or speeding across geographical boundaries, for some it's transversing needle and thread across the epidermis, writing our way into the thought patterns of industries, fields, and organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work, we achieve milestones, celebrate victories, and get rewarded duly, sometimes we have to deal with nasty bugs &lt;em&gt;(error, flaw, failure or fault in a computer program or system that causes it to produce an incorrect or unexpected result)&lt;/em&gt; every now and then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no matter what, we try our best to do the best work we can and be the best out there so whatever it is your hand finds to do, do it with pride, make the best out of it and cherish every moment you do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am Andrew Miracle, I help people fulfill their dreams, achieve their goals, innovate their process and make living efficient using software &amp;amp; technology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;industrialization&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><summary type="html">We work every day, somehow it seems like most of us were wired this way, some say the hustle is real or the struggle is, you can define yours anyway. If it isn't toiling with engines and machines, making glue stick, talking your way into people's heart or speeding across geographical boundaries, for some it's transversing needle and thread across the epidermis, writing our way into the thought patterns of industries, fields, and organizations.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">7 Valuable guides for Living</title><link href="/posts/valuable-guides-for-living" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 Valuable guides for Living" /><published>2019-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/valuable-guides-for-living</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/valuable-guides-for-living">&lt;p&gt;I was recently going through my document archive and found some age long advise I had given myself, which I consider very valuable advise to anyone, so here I am sharing it with you and I hope it turns out to be very useful to you too. These are my 7 valuable guides for living&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-know-what-you-have&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Know what you have&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is power, it’s rival is the illusion (the thought of knowledge that does not exist), if there is something you need to be sure of, make certain, information pertaining to what &lt;em&gt;skills&lt;/em&gt; you have, what &lt;em&gt;resource(s)&lt;/em&gt;, and how readily available these are to you, If you need to drive a nail into the wall, check your toolbox, whether you have a screwdriver or a hammer. Knowing what you have allows you to equip yourself efficiently for any task, challenge or opportunity ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-do-a-mental-audit-on-your-assets&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Do a mental audit on your assets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means you should put a number to what you have, what metric are you using to track your collection of information, how many certificates are associated with that academia you’ve optained, how much in ($) your favorite currency is all your assets, within your available competency can you list them out, like saying I’m proficient with (Photoshop, Sketch and Figma). So please do a mental audit on your asset (knowledge, money, information) and assign to them a metric for accountability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-value-what-you-have&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Value what you have&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the bus is age old, but can still shuttle from Lagos to Benin, value it, If you have a family that is yours, value them, someone who loves and cares for you should be valued, the little house, office, phone, laptop, audience, followers, congregation you have are extremely valuable and should be cherished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-use-what-you-have&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Use what you have&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a screw and need to drive a nail into the wall, find a way to get it done. You apparently are equipped with everything you need, trust your instincts, and put your thoughts to action, you can organize that event with friends and little to no sponsorship and it would be massive. The principle of using what you have drives down to achieving excellence with the resources that are available to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;5-the-fastest-way-to-solve-your-problem-is-to-find-those-who-have-that-problem-and-start-solving-it&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. The fastest way to solve your problem is to find those who have that problem and start solving it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve heard it in the past, &lt;strong&gt;two heads are better that one&lt;/strong&gt;, yeah you have also heard that &lt;strong&gt;problem shared is half solved&lt;/strong&gt;, the idea is not to moan about the problem without looking for a solution, but in finding people who share a similar problem, you may be able to identify the root cause of that problem faster, and much better ways to tackle such issues than the one you may have thought of implementing, as it is with Startups and Entrepreneurs today, Market research is a key element in the building phase of an MVP, more importantly because in sharing the problem with those who already have it and proposing a solution, you find innovative ways to deal with the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;6-every-problem-you-have-is-a-clue-to-a-problem-you-are-about-to-solve&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Every problem you have is a clue to a problem you are about to solve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software programmers will definitely understand this one, we face it everyday, solving one bug gives you insight to the next &lt;em&gt;bug&lt;/em&gt; you are about to solve. When a childs shoe lace looses while he is playing in the field, the present problem (loose shoe) is a gateway to learning how to tie a shoe lace properly, and in doing that, he also learns how to keep his shoes tight, the shoe is no longer a mystery. So look at the problem you are facing now, and i’m certain you can find an opportunity if you broaden you mind towards it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;7-keep-distributing-what-you-have&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Keep distributing what you have&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By distribution this is not limited to tangible, quantifiable resources, whatever you own can be shared, its a matter of choice, if you know something find ways to share it, not only does it thicken your knowledge, you just created a reference for that information when next you need it. the first rule is that you own this, so this is not about sharing something that crossed your way coincidentally, knowledge, assets, resources, find ways for it to outreach, take note that distrubution does not have to be free of charge, but its important that it also helps and solves a problem for the person who is getting access to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More importantly, play with the cards you’ve been dealt with, and if you dont have any &lt;strong&gt;BLUFF&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="journal" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html">I was recently going through my document archive and found some age long advise I had given myself, which I consider very valuable advise to anyone, so here I am sharing it with you and I hope it turns out to be very useful to you too. These are my 7 valuable guides for living</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/andrew.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">String Reversal in Javascript</title><link href="/posts/algorithms-js-string-reversal" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="String Reversal in Javascript" /><published>2019-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/algorithms-js-string-reversal</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/algorithms-js-string-reversal">&lt;p&gt;In this javascript algorithm, I would be sharing with us different methods to reverse a string in javascript.
This is a common exercise in coding interviews, entry level algorithm challenges, though implementation in various languages may be different we would be looking at how to reverse a string in javascript, hope this helps you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;task&quot;&gt;Task&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given a string, return a new string with the reversed order of characters&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;examples&quot;&gt;Examples&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reverse(‘apple’) === ‘leppa’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reverse(‘hello’) === ‘olleh’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reverse(‘Greetings!’) === ‘!sgniteerG’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-javascripts-inbuilt-array-prototypes&quot;&gt;Using Javascripts Inbuilt Array Prototypes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;join&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example above, we use the array methods, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;split&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;join&lt;/code&gt; if we executed the function, our output would be something like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;hello&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;//here we reverse the string hello&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// output here is an array ['h','e','l','l','o']&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// the output here is ['0','l','l','e','h']&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;join&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// The array join method would join the array into a string &quot;olleh&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-reduce-callback&quot;&gt;Using Reduce Callback&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reduce&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;acc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;curValue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;curValue&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;acc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reduce function takes an accumulator and a value, this function will loop through every element in an array an generate an output based on the expression we pass into it, here we reversely concatenate the elements of the array, a much clearer way to look at it is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stringToArray&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// This expression creates a new array from our string&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stringToArray&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reduce&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;acc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;curValue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;curValue&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;acc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-the-for-of-syntax&quot;&gt;Using the &lt;em&gt;For Of&lt;/em&gt; Syntax&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// we initially define reversed as an empty string in within the function&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reversed&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// The for of loop iterates over elements&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;character&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// var reversed = []&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// store the value into reversed recursively&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reversed&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;character&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reversed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// return the value of reveresed in our function&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reversed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The for Of loop can iterate through Arrays, Strings and Javascript constructs that return &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;propertyIsEnumerable&lt;/code&gt; arguement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/coding-interview-bootcamp-algorithms-and-data-structure/&quot;&gt;Learn More about Algorithms from : The Coding Interview Bootcamp: Algorithms + Data Structures &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="code" /><summary type="html">In this javascript algorithm, I would be sharing with us different methods to reverse a string in javascript. This is a common exercise in coding interviews, entry level algorithm challenges, though implementation in various languages may be different we would be looking at how to reverse a string in javascript, hope this helps you.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boiled Plaintain</title><link href="/posts/boiled-plantain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boiled Plaintain" /><published>2019-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/boiled-plantain</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/boiled-plantain">&lt;p&gt;Not so early this morning I had breakfast, not the usual kind but before we get to that let’s talk about the period before this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had harvested a bunch of plantain from the farm few days ago, unripe as they were, some had begun to get ripe, and today we had only one ripe plantain from the fold, my junior sister favour, the amazing chef at &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.facebook.com/besoma-kitchen&quot;&gt;Besoma Kitchen&lt;/a&gt; had decided she was going to preserve it till later today to make some Fri-ta-tas, while I hungry as I was this morning, saw the plantain as an opportunity to make a really nice breakfast combo of white rice, some boiled plaintain and vegetable sauce; not knowing about favour’s intention, I quickly did as my imagination had pieced together for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut the plantain and made my combo; favour coming into the kitchen seeing my actions, then screamed and said oooohhh I should have hidden it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes of course she should have, just like every entrepreneur should patent their idea, register their company and probably not wait for that time they think is best to initialize and start building their product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never wait because some hungry fellow from anywhere in the world or your brother could come in and do something with the idea, raw material, available opportunity you had and solve a similar problem be it (breakfast, lunch or dinner); the world is alway better without hunger :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So trust me you are better off starting now, and I mean right now, go back to that Kanban board or whatever and push that card to the in-progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lest I forget to mention, I ended up sharing my combo with favour.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="thinking" /><category term="journal" /><summary type="html">Not so early this morning I had breakfast, not the usual kind but before we get to that let’s talk about the period before this.</summary></entry></feed>