<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/journal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2019-11-21T03:57:49+00:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/journal/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Andrew Miracle | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Andrew is a Product Designer and Entrepreneur. My expertise is compassed from my years of experience in software development, Analytics and Technical Team Management.</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Nature, the Mother of Tech</title>
      <link href="/posts/nature-mother-of-tech" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nature, the Mother of Tech" />
      <published>2019-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/nature-mother-of-tech</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/nature-mother-of-tech">&lt;h1 id=&quot;draft-mode&quot;&gt;DRAFT MODE&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never really figured out the angle for this article, so I’ll just dump stuff here until it makes sense from a user point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Birds could fly before the wright brothers created the plane, possible to argue is the statement that they didn’t create the plane, according to their &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wright_brothers_patent_war&quot;&gt;patent&lt;/a&gt;, which stirred controversy for over a decade and even after their death. &lt;em&gt;The Wright brothers claimed to have created an aeronautical flying control system&lt;/em&gt; which proves that we were only trying to understand what nature had already designed, flight, which eagles and birds of all kinds have been utilizing, although the Wright brothers weren’t the only ones working on the invention of &lt;strong&gt;flight&lt;/strong&gt; systems during their time, why theirs succeded was because other inventors were more focused on creating highly efficient flight engines, without considering the conditions of the pilots who would control the plane, thus the Wright brothers were able to breakthrough because they designed from the Pilot’s perspective, doing so would enable them conduct further user experiments to improve flight control and efficiency, citing a case where nature is one step ahead of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nature and biology has already perfected theories which we today seek for in science and technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider machine learning and Neural networks, and How Trees already have a deep link of communication. Did you know that when cut the grass in your fields or pluck a freshly grown rose flower, the scent you perceive with your nose, as perfume from the flowers, or greens from the grass is actually a distress call to nature made my the flowers for ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning and Deep learning leverages the concept of neural networks and &lt;em&gt;decision trees&lt;/em&gt; in order to build highly complicated recommendation and learning systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trees today has VOCS and &lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/77/underworldsnbsp/never-underestimate-the-intelligence-of-trees&quot;&gt;mycorrhizae&lt;/a&gt; which allow them to shutdown or call for help, If you love foraging grasses and picnics you will realize that when you seat on the grass for so long, its only a matter of time before unfriendly insects begin to disturb your peace, because their neighbouring grasses have called for their help to push you human away from sitting down on them and suffocating them of air. piece of advise change your location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nature loves when tech is working in its favour, that’s why we find Cannabis and Agritech startups receiving the best in support they need. &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.crunchbase.com/news/twiga-foods-lands-over-30m-nairobis-largest-known-financing-round-of-the-year/&quot;&gt;Twiga Food lands over $30Million&lt;/a&gt; in Financing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neural networks existed within the deep roots of trees that allow them to share nutrients and communicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trees have their neural networks : The applications of deep learning are growing so vast that it has made a great headway into areas requiring heavy computing. And, the elements that make up DL models — artificial neural networks (ANN) — can be said to be the driving force behind the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1711.09784.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; Distilling a Neural Network Into a Soft Decision Tree, Hinton and Prosst tell why decision trees are preferred to elucidate neural nets. “Unlike the hidden units in a neural net, a typical node at the lower levels of a decision tree is only used by a very small fraction of the training data so the lower parts of the decision tree tend to overfit unless the size of the training set is exponentially large compared with the depth of the tree.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hinton and Frosst use the neural network itself to train on a decision tree. If large amounts of data are encountered, poor statistical efficiency observed in decision trees is nullified by neural nets. An important point here, ‘soft decision trees’ are considered to train the neural net. Soft decision trees mean children nodes (also known as the leaf or terminal node if it ends here) in a decision tree are assigned a certain probability. Also, all leaves contribute equally to the final decision in the tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chameleons can change their color according to their environment in order to blend in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bug and error reporting, Garbage collection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain today is trying to relive the same concepts of publicly immutable ledger where all transactions are recorded and known among all parties, today we relive that concepts already in childbirth, whereas we have smart contracts where two conditions meet for a transaction to be recorded on the ledger, in childbirth we have two more so dumb contract where consent is given by two parties and there is a constantly estimated time to arrival &lt;strong&gt;~9months&lt;/strong&gt; with which a transaction can be recorded as complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blockchain-and-childbirth&quot;&gt;Blockchain and Childbirth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain can be used to prove ownership when procuring or disposing of an asset. It can also help to track the history of an assets and related maintenance activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Blockchain is a type of diary or spreadsheet containing information about transactions. Each transaction generates a hash. … If a transaction is approved by a majority of the nodes then it is written into a block. Each block refers to the previous block and together make the Blockchain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;important-to-note&quot;&gt;Important to note&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AI exists because of Natural Intelligence (Today Chams can auto adapt- case study)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neural Networks existed within Trees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blockchain Networks are trying to do what DNA’s have been doing long time ago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what modern invention are we looking in tech today that we cannot link to nature.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="journal" />
      
        <category term="code" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Birds could fly before the Wright brothers created the plane, Neural networks existed within the deep roots of trees that allow them to share nutrients and communicate</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Your Manager wants you to succeed</title>
      <link href="/posts/manager-wants-your-success" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Your Manager wants you to succeed" />
      <published>2019-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/manager-wants-your-success</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/manager-wants-your-success">&lt;p&gt;We are wired to work, it’s our nature, to glorify God as we cultivate blessing from the created order and contribute value to others through the labor of our minds, hearts, and hands. For most of us this work greets us each Monday morning with a myriad of thorns and thistles. Sometimes we may struggle with our work or with our Managers, Head of Departments, Leaders etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Your manager wants you to succeed that's the hard truth&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the amount of pressure and expectation in our modern workplaces today, it could be hard to agree that your manager wants you to succeed. Sometimes they may not have the best way of showing it, however, you completing a task helps the company hit some KPI, meet their target and that means results, the type that can help the company’s decision making process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for someone who finds themselves under this form of management or leadership its very important that you should be able to :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-your-work-without-drama&quot;&gt;Do your work without drama&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No body likes to shout or talk too much, if you are given a task, get head on with it and clear it off with less drama and clutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;avoid-giving-excuses&quot;&gt;Avoid giving excuses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This accompanies the drama rule, don’t be or act like an incompetent or relegate yourself to the company liability list, don’t be a farm of excuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ask-questions-when-confused&quot;&gt;Ask questions when confused&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not the stupid ones of course, It is however beneficial to be able to communicate your confusion in a clear and concise manner, upper management staff usually don’t have a lot of time on their hands, so these fellows tend to appreciate concise and straight to the point approaches. It also goes to say that, If you’re having difficulties let them know before hand, however, this is not a license to be giving excuses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remember-the-pareto-principle&quot;&gt;Remember the Pareto Principle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You remember the 80/20 rule, yeah of course, this time around in the workplace you want to be among the 20% that’s responsible for 80% of the companies output, these output means result that’s helping your organization hit a target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More importantly be good at what you do. The truth is that your success is theirs too.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am aware that there could be edge cases where you could be dealing with a difficult manager or boss, if you do find yourself in such situation here’s a simple prayer, where I always find encouragement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lord Jesus, you know I am having a hard time loving that person at work. Their insensitive words and actions are so wounding and hurtful. I really want to avoid them and at times I want to retaliate against them. Lord, guard my heart from bitterness and resentment. Empower me to look for ways to bless them, to overcome evil with good, and to seek their flourishing. (Romans 12:17–19)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="journal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">We are wired to work, it's our nature, to glorify God as we cultivate blessing from the created order and contribute value to others through the labor of our minds, hearts, and hands.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Traditions and Cultures we learnt from our Forefathers</title>
      <link href="/posts/fetishes-our-forefathers-practiced" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Traditions and Cultures we learnt from our Forefathers" />
      <published>2019-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/fetishes-our-forefathers-practiced</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/fetishes-our-forefathers-practiced">&lt;p&gt;While growing up in the village, I observed that when elders gather, they always “litter” a portion of wine on the ground, making some incantations which include asking dead men to protect them! Of course the ancestors do not wake up and drink the palm wine. But “wasting” that palm wine is extremely important for a lot of reasons, one of which is safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One key thing I observed was that when the wine is poured on the ground, some elders check if ants congregate towards the wine. If ants do come towards the “littered” wine, it means the wine is not poisoned and safe for drinking. However if the wine is poured and ants do not come around, or either run away – That wine may not safe for drinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking a walk through the evening as you would expect on a Sunday through the streets of Lagos, you wouldn’t help but be amused at how young adults and teens pour libations with Star, Gulder, Orijin etc on cemented floors, when technically the packaging has reduced the possibility of poisoning, and African ants are not consumers of chemicalized beers! :D . Traditionally, on safety frameworks, there is no reason for that. But most people imitate without knowing the basis of the pouring. Yes, you can pray with your &lt;strong&gt;'’foreign’‘&lt;/strong&gt; beer without a need to waste any portion of it, now you can say your prayer with knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not imitate the old without full knowledge of the intentions and consequences.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="journal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">While growing up in the village, I observed that when elders gather, they always “litter” a portion of wine on the ground</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Defining who we are</title>
      <link href="/posts/humans-and-work" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Defining who we are" />
      <published>2019-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/humans-and-work</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/humans-and-work">&lt;p&gt;We work every day, somehow it seems like most of us were wired this way, some say the hustle is real or the struggle is, you can define yours anyway. If it isn't toiling with engines and machines, making glue stick, talking your way into people's heart or speeding across geographical boundaries, for some it's transversing needle and thread across the epidermis, writing our way into the thought patterns of industries, fields, and organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work, we achieve milestones, celebrate victories, and get rewarded duly, sometimes we have to deal with nasty bugs &lt;em&gt;(error, flaw, failure or fault in a computer program or system that causes it to produce an incorrect or unexpected result)&lt;/em&gt; every now and then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no matter what, we try our best to do the best work we can and be the best out there so whatever it is your hand finds to do, do it with pride, make the best out of it and cherish every moment you do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am Andrew Miracle, I help people fulfill their dreams, achieve their goals, innovate their process and make living efficient using software &amp;amp; technology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;industrialization&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do?&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="journal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">We work every day, somehow it seems like most of us were wired this way, some say the hustle is real or the struggle is, you can define yours anyway. If it isn't toiling with engines and machines, making glue stick, talking your way into people's heart or speeding across geographical boundaries, for some it's transversing needle and thread across the epidermis, writing our way into the thought patterns of industries, fields, and organizations.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">7 Valuable guides for Living</title>
      <link href="/posts/valuable-guides-for-living" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 Valuable guides for Living" />
      <published>2019-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/valuable-guides-for-living</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/valuable-guides-for-living">&lt;p&gt;I was recently going through my document archive and found some age long advise I had given myself, which I consider very valuable advise to anyone, so here I am sharing it with you and I hope it turns out to be very useful to you too. These are my 7 valuable guides for living&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-know-what-you-have&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Know what you have&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is power, it’s rival is the illusion (the thought of knowledge that does not exist), if there is something you need to be sure of, make certain, information pertaining to what &lt;em&gt;skills&lt;/em&gt; you have, what &lt;em&gt;resource(s)&lt;/em&gt;, and how readily available these are to you, If you need to drive a nail into the wall, check your toolbox, whether you have a screwdriver or a hammer. Knowing what you have allows you to equip yourself efficiently for any task, challenge or opportunity ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-do-a-mental-audit-on-your-assets&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Do a mental audit on your assets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means you should put a number to what you have, what metric are you using to track your collection of information, how many certificates are associated with that academia you’ve optained, how much in ($) your favorite currency is all your assets, within your available competency can you list them out, like saying I’m proficient with (Photoshop, Sketch and Figma). So please do a mental audit on your asset (knowledge, money, information) and assign to them a metric for accountability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-value-what-you-have&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Value what you have&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the bus is age old, but can still shuttle from Lagos to Benin, value it, If you have a family that is yours, value them, someone who loves and cares for you should be valued, the little house, office, phone, laptop, audience, followers, congregation you have are extremely valuable and should be cherished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-use-what-you-have&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Use what you have&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a screw and need to drive a nail into the wall, find a way to get it done. You apparently are equipped with everything you need, trust your instincts, and put your thoughts to action, you can organize that event with friends and little to no sponsorship and it would be massive. The principle of using what you have drives down to achieving excellence with the resources that are available to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;5-the-fastest-way-to-solve-your-problem-is-to-find-those-who-have-that-problem-and-start-solving-it&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. The fastest way to solve your problem is to find those who have that problem and start solving it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve heard it in the past, &lt;strong&gt;two heads are better that one&lt;/strong&gt;, yeah you have also heard that &lt;strong&gt;problem shared is half solved&lt;/strong&gt;, the idea is not to moan about the problem without looking for a solution, but in finding people who share a similar problem, you may be able to identify the root cause of that problem faster, and much better ways to tackle such issues than the one you may have thought of implementing, as it is with Startups and Entrepreneurs today, Market research is a key element in the building phase of an MVP, more importantly because in sharing the problem with those who already have it and proposing a solution, you find innovative ways to deal with the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;6-every-problem-you-have-is-a-clue-to-a-problem-you-are-about-to-solve&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Every problem you have is a clue to a problem you are about to solve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software programmers will definitely understand this one, we face it everyday, solving one bug gives you insight to the next &lt;em&gt;bug&lt;/em&gt; you are about to solve. When a childs shoe lace looses while he is playing in the field, the present problem (loose shoe) is a gateway to learning how to tie a shoe lace properly, and in doing that, he also learns how to keep his shoes tight, the shoe is no longer a mystery. So look at the problem you are facing now, and i’m certain you can find an opportunity if you broaden you mind towards it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;7-keep-distributing-what-you-have&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Keep distributing what you have&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By distribution this is not limited to tangible, quantifiable resources, whatever you own can be shared, its a matter of choice, if you know something find ways to share it, not only does it thicken your knowledge, you just created a reference for that information when next you need it. the first rule is that you own this, so this is not about sharing something that crossed your way coincidentally, knowledge, assets, resources, find ways for it to outreach, take note that distrubution does not have to be free of charge, but its important that it also helps and solves a problem for the person who is getting access to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More importantly, play with the cards you’ve been dealt with, and if you dont have any &lt;strong&gt;BLUFF&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="journal" />
      
        <category term="life" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I was recently going through my document archive and found some age long advise I had given myself, which I consider very valuable advise to anyone, so here I am sharing it with you and I hope it turns out to be very useful to you too. These are my 7 valuable guides for living</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/andrew.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Boiled Plaintain</title>
      <link href="/posts/boiled-plantain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boiled Plaintain" />
      <published>2019-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/boiled-plantain</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/boiled-plantain">&lt;p&gt;Not so early this morning I had breakfast, not the usual kind but before we get to that let’s talk about the period before this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had harvested a bunch of plantain from the farm few days ago, unripe as they were, some had begun to get ripe, and today we had only one ripe plantain from the fold, my junior sister favour, the amazing chef at &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.facebook.com/besoma-kitchen&quot;&gt;Besoma Kitchen&lt;/a&gt; had decided she was going to preserve it till later today to make some Fri-ta-tas, while I hungry as I was this morning, saw the plantain as an opportunity to make a really nice breakfast combo of white rice, some boiled plaintain and vegetable sauce; not knowing about favour’s intention, I quickly did as my imagination had pieced together for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut the plantain and made my combo; favour coming into the kitchen seeing my actions, then screamed and said oooohhh I should have hidden it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes of course she should have, just like every entrepreneur should patent their idea, register their company and probably not wait for that time they think is best to initialize and start building their product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never wait because some hungry fellow from anywhere in the world or your brother could come in and do something with the idea, raw material, available opportunity you had and solve a similar problem be it (breakfast, lunch or dinner); the world is alway better without hunger :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So trust me you are better off starting now, and I mean right now, go back to that Kanban board or whatever and push that card to the in-progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lest I forget to mention, I ended up sharing my combo with favour.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="thinking" />
      
        <category term="journal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Not so early this morning I had breakfast, not the usual kind but before we get to that let’s talk about the period before this.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Deadlines or Lifeline ?</title>
      <link href="/posts/deadline-vs-lifeline" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deadlines or Lifeline ?" />
      <published>2019-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/deadline-vs-lifeline</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/deadline-vs-lifeline">&lt;p&gt;We are stuck goals and milestones in a modern age, where everything is moving fast and millenials are expected to meet very high expectations, with a rise in productivity tools like Trello, Asana and mantras like kanban, GTD or Getting Things Done has grown in adoption in this century due to the ever demanding need to be more productive. As Project Managers or startup founders you many have come to a situation where you gave a developer a job to do for you with an ETA only to be dissapointed with &lt;strong&gt;Low Delivery or No Delivery&lt;/strong&gt; at all. This event is experienced when working with most creatives, artist, tailors, music producers, carpenters etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let me ask you, Are you a &lt;strong&gt;deadline&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;lifeline&lt;/strong&gt; person ?
Incase you’re curious to find out, this comparison should help&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deadline&quot;&gt;Deadline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sticks to the timeline and delivers before time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sticks to a particular process/strategy and gracefully follows it through&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lifeline&quot;&gt;Lifeline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good at emergency deliveries, tight delivery expectations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hacks processes to produces optimal results, most cases short term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes me reflect between Mourinho and Pep Guardiola, two wonderful personalites, winners they are, however I would categorize one as a Lifeline person and another one as a deadline person&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the startup world, you require a mix of both, roll out a feature as soon as the need arises, so that the Investors and users would be happy, experiencing the potential of that feature, without sacrificing the position of consistent iteration over a process, flow, or major release to add that grand appeal to your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need processes and consistent behaviour to be meet deadlines once you have actionable goals, wheareas you could pray for miracles, or an all-star teammate to pull a lifeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who are you ? Deadline : Lifeline&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="journal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">As Project Managers or startup founders you many have come to a situation where you gave a developer a job to do for you with an ETA only to be dissapointed with</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">What can a course in programming to do you ?</title>
      <link href="/posts/what-can-programming-do-for-me" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What can a course in programming to do you ?" />
      <published>2019-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/what-can-programming-do-for-me</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/what-can-programming-do-for-me">&lt;p&gt;So you may be wondering what benefits you get from learning how to code, apart from the obvious benefits, learning how to code can help you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve your perception and thought process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add value to your current role or position&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teach you discipline as (programming requires discipline)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Help you get a job (There are a lot of testimonies out there about totally beginners getting a job after completing a coding program)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very easy to get started with online resources that make it easy and have a very welcoming community where you can learn from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Have you considered learning to code&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org/&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com/&quot;&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udacity.com/&quot;&gt;Udacity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/&quot;&gt;Cousera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://favcode54.org/&quot;&gt;Favcode54&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/&quot;&gt;EDX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/&quot;&gt;Udemy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not convinced yet, these are life changing testimonies from people who after taking a course in programming improved and transformed their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glamour.com/story/i-am-a-woman-who-learned-to-code-and-it-changed-my-life&quot;&gt;I’m a Woman Who Learned to Code and, Honestly, It Changed My Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/inspirational-success-stories-from-self-taught-web-developers-4f6f375cf17d&quot;&gt;Lessons from 7 self-taught coders who now work full time as software developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://favcodereviews.com/&quot;&gt;Student Testimonies from Favcode54&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com/stories&quot;&gt;Student Testimonies from Codecademy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@Jasraj/so-i-got-a-front-end-dev-job-after-almost-12-months-on-freecodecamp-9e8b4712e0e4&quot;&gt;I just got a Front End Dev job. And I have freeCodeCamp to thank for it…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org/stories&quot;&gt;FCC Testimonies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="code" />
      
        <category term="journal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">So you may be wondering what benefits you get from learning how to code, apart from the obvious benefits, learning how to code can help you</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">After Software Development what next ?</title>
      <link href="/posts/after-software-development-what-next" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="After Software Development what next ?" />
      <published>2019-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/after-software-development-what-next</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/after-software-development-what-next">&lt;p&gt;I recently came across an acquaintaince who had about 20 years of experience in the software development field, and was wondering what next he should do at this point in his career and life, though I didnt have the opportunity to share my answers to him, at the top of my head, these were my thoughts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mentorship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;management&quot;&gt;Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With over 20 years in your belt, you should have the opportunity to notice how trends have been shaped, improved and change, move to the top of the Product Development Cycle which is either &lt;strong&gt;(idea =&amp;gt; design)&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;em&gt;(design =&amp;gt; implementation)&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;(design =&amp;gt; user adoption)&lt;/strong&gt; you should be able to match any of these with your personal capacity and strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mentorship&quot;&gt;Mentorship&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give back to the community, what is it that you have learnt over this years that you can share with the younger generation of budding software developers and enthusiasts, trust me, its a very lonely journey for those starting and having someone with long term experience to talk to can be de-stressing and comforting, the side benefit is that, it helps you keep up with the latest trends in technology and also keep you abreast with industry trends too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, after spending over 20 years in any field, I tend think that there are a broad spectrum of choices after that long period of time,with which anyone should be able to discover a path, specialization and unique industry-relevant edge that aligns with their skill set and strengths as an individual, this would be the area(s) where they can focus the remaining part of their time and energy on.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="journal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I recently came across an acquaintaince who had about 20 years of experience in the software development field, and was wondering what next he should do at this point in his career and life, though I didnt have the opportunity to share my answers to him, at the top of my head, these were my thoughts</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Lessons learned from building for startups</title>
      <link href="/posts/lessons-learned-from-startups" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lessons learned from building for startups" />
      <published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/lessons-learned-from-startups</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/lessons-learned-from-startups">&lt;p&gt;Although we’d like to develop products and services iteratively, the truth is organisations think in terms of strict deadlines – and budgets. We product owners need to think about how we manage this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browsers update regularly, making frequent, (mostly) small changes. This causes little disruption for users. It’s rare you’ll download a big update and find everything is completely different. This is is how we’d like to develop software over several years, especially with embedded systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let’s say you have a finite budget and, consequently, a set-in-stone launch date – like the ship in the above picture. The expectation is that the product will be ready, and won’t sink if it bumps into any icebergs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your best feedback will come from real usage, you might plan a beta phase, as we did when developing library self-service software. This is useful,but there’s a big difference between a controlled roll out to 4 small libraries, and installing kiosks in over 20 libraries within various institutions in a region, where staff are less invested in the new product and require understanding to be able to utilize the benefits of the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We unearthed user problems during the launch I would have liked to have fixed more quickly, but we ran up against the big launch date curse of &lt;em&gt;no more project money&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lesson learned is therefore quite simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;If you have an official launch date, make sure there is some project budget remaining for further changes after this date.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: It’s important this money is kept aside for the project. There’s little value in coming in under budget (besides some temporary good PR that’ll come back to bite you later in your career) if your product isn’t perfect – and it’ll never be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Andrew Miracle</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="web" />
      
        <category term="startups" />
      
        <category term="journal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Although we’d like to develop products and services iteratively, the truth is organisations think in terms of strict deadlines – and budgets. We product owners need to think about how we manage this.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
