<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/teams/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2019-11-17T21:55:33+00:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/teams/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Andrew Miracle | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Andrew is a Product Designer and Entrepreneur. My expertise is compassed from my years of experience in software development, Analytics and Technical Team Management.</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Objective Driven Team Structure</title>
      <link href="/posts/result-oriented-teams" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Objective Driven Team Structure" />
      <published>2019-11-17T21:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-11-17T21:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/result-oriented-teams</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/result-oriented-teams">&lt;p&gt;Team members are often chosen for the wrong reasons: for example, they are often chosen because they have an interest in the project, because their wage is affordable, or most often simply because they are available. They are not chosen with objective actualization in mind. This brings to attention the need for developing a team formation structure that is focused on optimal output. &lt;strong&gt;Structuring teams for optimal output are at the core of the Result Driven Team Methodology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adopting from the (OKR Playbook)[https://weekdone.com/resources/objectives-key-results] (Objectives and Key Results), a popular management strategy for goal setting within organizations driven by connecting companies, teams and personal goals to measurable results while having all team members and leaders work together in one, unified direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-objective-driven-team-structures&quot;&gt;What are Objective Driven Team Structures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first consideration in organizing a team is to determine the team’s broad objective. Here are the broad objectives according to Larson and LaFasto&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Problem resolution
• Creativity
• Tactical execution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve established the broad objective, you choose a team structure that matches it. Larson and LaFasto define three general team structures for effective, high-performance team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes more than just a group of people who happen to work together to constitute a team. In thek book The Wisdom of Teams, Katzenbach and Smith (1993) define a team as “a small number of people with complementary skills who are committed to a common purpose, performance goals, and approach for which they hold themselves mutually accountable.” Teamwork can come into play on software projects on any number of spescific tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;objective-driven-teams-are-result-driven-teams-and-have-essential-characteristics&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective driven teams are result driven teams and have essential characteristics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Steve’s (Rapid Development)[www.AMAZON_LINK.com], there are four essential characteristics of a results-driven team structure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roles must be clear, and everyone must be accountable for their work at all times. Accountability is critical to effective decision making and to rapid execution after the decisions have been made.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The team must have an effective communication system that supports the free flow of information among team members. Communication must flow freely both from and to the team’s management.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The team must have some means of monitoring individual performance and providing feedback. The team should know whom to reward, who needs  individual development, and who can assume more responsibilities in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decisions must be made based on facts rather than on subjective opinions whenever possible. The team needs to be sure that the facts are interpreted without biases that undercut the functioning of the team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a strong desire to contribute among team members of Objective Driven teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team members are committed to the team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is an indentifiable level of inter-dependence among team members - team members learn to rely on each other to accomplish certain tasks and goals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A sense of Autonomy among team members, with little to no interference, according to research, when there is a problem instead of managers taking it upon themselves to punish or solve these issues, they should rather walk by the side of the teams to point them in the right direction for how to go about their blocks or productivity conflict&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strong sense of Empowerment among team members, Team members feel like they have the power to use up the resources and privileges available to them for the benefit of the team, Learning from the rework project, Google gives their engineers access to their codebase which is worth an incredible wealth of knowledge for new engineers to explore and make input into the processes at the heart of the organization.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High level of enjoyment, in Objective Driven teams, due to the massive gains of accomplished goals and milestones, team members tend to take happiness seriously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;achieving-objective-driven-team-structures&quot;&gt;Achieving Objective Driven Team Structures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manage Teams as Teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In team selection, ensure there is a blend of technical, business, management and inter-personal skills, of course this would vary across various disciplines and not only apply to the world or business or startups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure that team members obtain specific soft skills, or collaboration skills required to work effectively with others, if communications is aligned with slack or issues are traiged with github, team leads and managers should ensure that all team members are fully acquainted with the resource and knowledge to use these tools and frameworks in order to streamline communication and collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-call-for-the-need-for-result-driven-team-structures-so-what-are-these-result-driven-teams-are-driven-by-a-common-goal-and-vision-and-are-invested-in-the-same-amount-of-work-and-tide-so-they-work-on-how-to-make-things&quot;&gt;This call for the need for result driven team structures, so what are these, result driven teams are driven by a common goal and vision and are invested in the same amount of work and tide, so they work on how to make things.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, a lot of reading can try to point you to the right direction as to how to achieve this goals, I decided to highlight these characteristics so that you as team members can identify the state of your team and take action.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="teams" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Team members are often chosen for the wrong reasons: for example, they are often chosen because they have an interest in the project, because their wage is affordable, or most often simply because they are available. They are not chosen with objective actualization in mind. This brings to attention the need for developing a team formation structure that is focused on optimal output. Structuring teams for optimal output are at the core of the Result Driven Team Methodology</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Why do teams fail ?</title>
      <link href="/posts/why-teams-fail" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why do teams fail ?" />
      <published>2019-11-15T21:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-11-15T21:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/why-teams-fail</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/why-teams-fail">&lt;p&gt;Most team problems are associated with an inefficiency in MOI, which stands for Motivation, Organization and Information, evidence from regressive teams prove that the lack of initial motivation and drive, or a clear sense of hierachy, structure and rules of engagement in organizations and even the lack of resource to consume in order to understand how to accomplish goals breaks down a majority of teams formed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see this illustrated in our everyday life from our favorite sports, bands, groups in a varying array, a major number of successful teams in the face of these constraints have two things in common, these teams have a SWAT and a Supporter as part of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term SWAT adopted from from Steve McConell’s work is an acronym for &lt;em&gt;Skilled With Advanced Tools&lt;/em&gt;, this refers to a specific individual that possess domain specific knowlege, or deep technical skills in an platform, area, framework or language, a SWAT is a master in his field and understands all the code and nuances of his subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas we adapt the Supporter role from Dr. Meredith Belbins research on Team Leadership roles based on Action Oriented, Thought Oriented and People Oriented Team structures, He explains that a supporter builds on team members’ strengths and underpins their
shortcomings. Provides emotional leadership and fosters team spirit. Improves communications among team members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-references-here-are-a-quick-rundown-of-all-leadership-roles-from-belbins-work&quot;&gt;For References here are a quick rundown of all Leadership Roles from Belbin’s work&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Driver: controls team direction at a. detailed, tactical level. Defines things, steers and shapes group discussions and activities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coordinator: controls team direction at the highest, strategic level. Moves the problem-solving forward by recognizing strengths and weaknesses and making the best use of human and other resources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Originator: provides leadership in ideas, innovating and inventing ideas and strategies, especially on major issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monitor: analyzes problems from a practical point of view and evaluates ideas and suggestions so that the team can make balanced decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Implementer: converts concepts and plans into work procedures and carries out group plans efficiently and as agreed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investigator—Explores and reports on ideas, developments, and resources outside the group. Creates external contacts that may be useful to the group.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finisher—Ensures that all necessary work is completed in all details. Seeks work that needs greater than average attention to detail, and maintains the group’s focus and sense of urgency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the years, Dr. Belbin’s research has immersed into team structures which you might find interesting to dig further into (Team roles Belbin)[https://www.belbin.com/about/belbin-team-roles/]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently as much as we may want to pose that most teams fail, we must understand that failure is a state of the mind, from the IBM Design Playbook, as Multidisciplinary independent teams focused on a Hill, it is important to fail fast, regarding failure as a learning opportunity, in order words, fail fast and iterate quickly. As Thato Rammoko quotes &lt;strong&gt;Humans never fail, We only run out of Time, Scope or Capacity&lt;/strong&gt; The TSC arguement is a topic for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-do-teams-fail-&quot;&gt;Why do Teams Fail ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Autonomy, this can be related to the Diverse Talented team in the IBM Design Thinking Course, where teams should be bound by a common goal and objective, not by processes, identifying&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MOI, Motivation, Objective, I***&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supporter, every team needs a supporter, a common arguement within this brings about the need for gender balance among teams, because in over 50% of the time, females are more empathic than their male fellow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not deciding on a conflict resolution framework, most people try to shy away from conflict so they don’t hurt their team mates feelings, establishing a line of action in case of conflict and opening up communication can save a team from breaking up during conflicts. acccording to Tukman’s law[link], this stage commonly referred to as the storming stage is completely inevitable and would eventually come, what is best is for the team to get past this cycle. The truth is that at the point of any major breakthrough, the most successful team had to navigate past their storm stage to get to where they are today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;indicators-a-dysfunctional-team&quot;&gt;Indicators a Dysfunctional Team&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cohesiveness of a group depends on the total field of forces that act on that group. Taking to account the models that direct the formation of teams, from (Corporate Skunkworks team )[https://fortune.com/2017/06/15/corporate-skunkworks-innovation-startups-facebook-oracle-walmart/], Feature Teams, SWAT (Special Weapons And Tactics) Teams, Feature Teams, being able to idenity a point of instability within the team can help towards streamlining objectives and goals amongst members even better, Signs that a team isn’t functioning well are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rigidity among roles being played.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack of commitment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack of Trust and Mutual confidence, Larson has stated that Trust hangs on Honesty, Opennes, Consistency and Respect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This are a few indicators among others, just as team structures are chosen for the wrong reasons, team members are often chosen for the wrong reasons: for example, they are often chosen because they have an interest in the project, because their wage is affordable, or most
often simply because they are available. They are not chosen with objective actualization in mind. This brings to attention the need for developing a team formation structure that is focused on optimal output. &lt;strong&gt;Structuring teams for optimal output are at the core of the Result Driven Team Methodology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-result-driven-team-structures&quot;&gt;What are Result Driven Team Structures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first consideration in organizing a team is to determine the team’s broad objective. Here are the broad objectives according to Larson and LaFasto&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Problem resolution
• Creativity
• Tactical execution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve established the broad objective, you choose a team structure that matches it. Larson and LaFasto define three general team structures for effective, high-performance team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes more than just a group of people who happen to work together to constitute a team. In thek book The Wisdom of Teams, Katzenbach and Smith (1993) define a team as “a small number of people with complementary skills who are committed to a common purpose, performance goals, and approach for which they hold themselves mutually accountable.” Teamwork can come into play on software projects on any number of spescific tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;essential-characteristics-of-result-driven-teams&quot;&gt;Essential Characteristics of Result Driven Teams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Steve’s (Rapid Development)[www.AMAZON_LINK.com], there are four essential characteristics of a results-driven team structure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roles must be clear, and everyone must be accountable for their work at all times. Accountability is critical to effective decision making and to rapid execution after the decisions have been made.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The team must have an effective communication system that supports the free flow of information among team members. Communication must flow freely both from and to the team’s management.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The team must have some means of monitoring individual performance and providing feedback. The team should know whom to reward, who needs  individual development, and who can assume more responsibilities in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decisions must be made based on facts rather than on subjective opinions whenever possible. The team needs to be sure that the facts are interpreted without biases that undercut the functioning of the team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a strong desire to contribute among team members of Result Driven teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team members are committed to the team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is an indentifiable level of inter-dependence among team members - team members learn to rely on each other to accomplish certain tasks and goals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A sense of Autonomy among team members, with little to no interference, according to research, when there is a problem instead of managers taking it upon themselves to punish or solve these issues, they should rather walk by the side of the teams to point them in the right direction for how to go about their blocks or productivity conflict&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strong sense of Empowerment among team members, Team members feel like they have the power to use up the resources and privileges available to them for the benefit of the team, Learning from the rework project, Google gives their engineers access to their codebase which is worth an incredible wealth of knowledge for new engineers to explore and make input into the processes at the heart of the organization.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High level of enjoyment, in Result Driven teams, due to the massive gains of accomplished goals and milestones, team members tend to take happiness seriously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;achieving-result-driven-team-structures&quot;&gt;Achieving Result Driven Team Structures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manage Teams as Teams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In team selection, ensure there is a blend of technical, business, management and inter-personal skills, of course this would vary across various disciplines and not only apply to the world or business or startups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure that team members obtain specific soft skills, or collaboration skills required to work effectively with others, if communications is aligned with slack or issues are traiged with github, team leads and managers should ensure that all team members are fully acquainted with the resource and knowledge to use these tools and frameworks in order to streamline communication and collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-call-for-the-need-for-result-driven-team-structures-so-what-are-these-result-driven-teams-are-driven-by-a-common-goal-and-vision-and-are-invested-in-the-same-amount-of-work-and-tide-so-they-work-on-how-to-make-things&quot;&gt;This call for the need for result driven team structures, so what are these, result driven teams are driven by a common goal and vision and are invested in the same amount of work and tide, so they work on how to make things.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, a lot of reading can try to point you to the right direction as to how to achieve this goals, I decided to highlight these characteristics so that you as team members can identify the state of your team and take action.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="teams" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Most team problems are associated with an inefficiency in MOI, which stands for Motivation, Organization and Information, evidence from regressive teams prove that the lack of initial motivation and drive, or a clear sense of hierachy, structure and rules of engagement in organizations and even the lack of resource to consume in order to understand how to accomplish goals breaks down a majority of teams formed.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
