<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/teams/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-08-04T23:44:33+00:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/teams/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Andrew Miracle | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Andrew is a Product Designer and Entrepreneur. My expertise is compassed from my years of experience in software development, Analytics and Technical Team Management.</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Team Leadership Roles</title>
      <link href="/posts/team-leadership-roles" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Team Leadership Roles" />
      <published>2019-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/team-leadership-roles</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/team-leadership-roles">&lt;p&gt;From Dr. Meredith Belbins research on Team Leadership roles based on Action-Oriented, Thought Oriented and People-Oriented Team structures, He, Belbin defines a ‘team role’ as “a tendency to behave, contribute and interrelate with others in a particular way”. Therefore, by analysing how leadership is effected in teams you can categorise team leaders into the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Driver: controls team direction at a. detailed, tactical level.  Defines things, steers and shapes group discussions and activities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coordinator: controls the team’s direction at the highest, strategic level. Moves the problem-solving forward by recognizing strengths and weaknesses and making the best use of human and other resources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Originator: provides leadership in ideas, innovating and inventing ideas and strategies, especially on major issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monitor: analyzes problems from a practical point of view and evaluates ideas and suggestions so that the team can make balanced decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Implementer: converts concepts and plans into work procedures and carry out the group’s plans efficiently and as agreed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investigator—Explores and reports on ideas, developments, and resources outside the group. Creates external contacts that may be useful to the group.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finisher—Ensures that all necessary work is completed in all details. Seeks work that needs greater than average attention to detail,  and maintains the group’s focus and sense of urgency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Dr Meredith Belbin decided to investigate the way teams of executives tackled a team-oriented task at the Henley Management College in the 1960s, it is unlikely he expected the results to still be used all over the world 50 years later. However, the Belbin Team Roles model, finally published in his 1981 book ‘Management Teams’, is commonly used for identifying the roles individuals play in their teams and how these roles can be combined to maximise performance. If you find this interesting you can dig further &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.belbin.com/about/belbin-team-roles/&quot;&gt;Team roles Belbin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="teams" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">From Dr. Meredith Belbins research on Team Leadership roles based on Action-Oriented, Thought Oriented and People-Oriented Team structures, He, Belbin defines a ‘team role’ as “a tendency to behave, contribute and interrelate with others in a particular way”. Therefore, by analysing how leadership is effected in teams you can categorise team leaders into the following.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Objective Driven Team Structure</title>
      <link href="/posts/result-oriented-teams" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Objective Driven Team Structure" />
      <published>2019-11-17T21:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-11-17T21:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/result-oriented-teams</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/result-oriented-teams">&lt;p&gt;Team members are often chosen for the wrong reasons: for example, they are often chosen because they have an interest in the project, because their wage is affordable, or most often simply because they are available. They are not chosen with Result Actualization based on Project objectives in mind. This brings to attention the need for developing a team formation structure with a focus on optimal output. &lt;strong&gt;Structuring teams for optimal output are at the core of the Result Driven Team Methodology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adopting from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://weekdone.com/resources/objectives-key-results&quot;&gt;OKR Playbook&lt;/a&gt; (Objectives and Key Results), a popular management strategy for goal setting within organizations driven by connecting companies, teams and personal goals to measurable results, Result Driven Teams are the Same as Objective Driven Teams (ODT), we take a look at some of the What and Hows of ODT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-objective-driven-team-structures&quot;&gt;What are Objective Driven Team Structures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first consideration in organizing a team is to determine the team’s broad objective. Let’s take a look at the Larson and Lafasto broad objectives template:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Problem resolution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creativity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tactical execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve established the broad objective, you choose a team structure that matches it. Larson and LaFasto define three general team structures for effective, high-performance team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes more than just a group of people who happen to work together to constitute a team. In the book, The Wisdom of Teams, Katzenbach and Smith (1993) define a team as “a small number of people with complementary skills who are committed to a common purpose, performance goals, and approach for which they hold themselves mutually accountable.” Teamwork can come into play on various projects types as well as in software development on any number of specific tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;objective-driven-teams-have-essential-these-characteristics&quot;&gt;Objective driven teams have essential these characteristics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Steve’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Rapid-Development-Taming-Software-Schedules/dp/1556159005&quot;&gt;Rapid Development&lt;/a&gt;, there are four essential characteristics of a results-driven team structure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Roles must be clear, and everyone must be accountable for their work at all times. Accountability is critical to effective decision making and to rapid execution after the decisions have been made.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The team must have an effective communication system that supports the free flow of information among team members. Communication must flow freely both from and to the team’s management.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The team must have some means of monitoring individual performance and providing feedback. The team should know whom to reward, who needs individual development, and who can assume more responsibilities in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Decisions must be made based on facts rather than on subjective opinions whenever possible. The team needs to be sure that the facts are interpreted without biases that undercut the functioning of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;achieving-objective-driven-team-structures&quot;&gt;Achieving Objective Driven Team Structures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Manage Teams as Teams, with little to no interference, when there is a problem instead of team leads taking it upon themselves to punish or solve these issues, they should rather walk by the side of the team member to point them in the right direction for how to go about their blocks or productivity conflict&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create an accomodating environment for contribution from team members, in what ever way they intend to deliver on set goals based on guidelines instead of strict process adherence. Examples, A teammate may choose to take down minutes from a standup with a recording device, or pen and paper or simply type on their laptop, achieving the goals should be core focus and less on the process.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In team selection, ensure there is a blend of technical, business, management and interpersonal skills, of course this would vary across various disciplines and not only apply to the world or business or startups.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ensure that team members obtain specific soft skills, or collaboration skills required to work effectively with others, if communications are aligned with slack or issues are triaged with github, team leads and managers should ensure that all team members are fully acquainted with the resource and knowledge to use these tools and frameworks in order to streamline communication and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective driven teams are driven by a common goal and vision and are invested in the same amount of work and tide, doing this results in massive gains of accomplished goals and milestones, where team members tend to take happiness seriously and experience high levels of enjoyment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, a lot of reading can try to point you to the right direction as to how to achieve these goals, I decided to highlight these characteristics so that you as team members can identify the state of your team and take action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you found this insightful, I’m still curious and hope you are too — What do you think are the best ways to pioneer teams towards results and objective actualization ? Please, share them in the comments and help us all build better and stronger teams.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="teams" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Team members are often chosen for the wrong reasons: for example, they are often chosen because they have an interest in the project, because their wage is affordable, or most often simply because they are available. They are not chosen with Result Actualization based on Project objectives in mind. This brings to attention the need for developing a team formation structure with a focus on optimal output. Structuring teams for optimal output are at the core of the Result Driven Team Methodology</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Why do teams fail ?</title>
      <link href="/posts/why-teams-fail" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why do teams fail ?" />
      <published>2019-11-15T21:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-11-15T21:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/why-teams-fail</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/why-teams-fail">&lt;p&gt;Retrogressive teams are usually characterized by a lack in MOI, which is an acronym for Motivation, Organization and  Information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lack of energy and drive can be detrimental to teams right after formation, considering that motivation is spawned in stages, team leaders should invest time and effort into keeping energy levels high at all time. A clear sense of hierarchy, structure and rules of engagement in organizations can keep team members prepared on how to deliver results whereas the lack of resources to consume for the purpose of understanding how to accomplish goals break down a majority of teams right after formation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see this illustrated in our everyday life from our favourite sports, bands, groups in a varying array, a major number of successful teams in the face of these constraints have two things in common, these teams have a SWAT and a Supporter as part of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term &lt;strong&gt;SWAT&lt;/strong&gt; adopted from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Rapid-Development-Taming-Software-Schedules/dp/1556159005&quot;&gt;Steve McConnell’s&lt;/a&gt; work is an acronym for Skilled With Advanced Tools, this refers to a specific individual that possess domain-specific knowledge, or deep technical skills in a platform, area, framework or language, a SWAT is a master in his field and understands all the code and nuances of his subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas we learn about the &lt;strong&gt;Supporter&lt;/strong&gt; from Dr. Meredith Belbins research on &lt;a href=&quot;https://andrewmiracle.com/posts/team-leadership-roles&quot;&gt;Team Leadership&lt;/a&gt; based on People-Oriented Team structures. Here he defines a Supporter, as a person who builds on team members’ strengths and underpins their shortcomings. A supporter Provides emotional leadership and fosters team spirit to improve communications among team members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently as much as we may want to pose that most teams fail, we must understand that failure is a state of the mind, from the IBM Design Thinking Playbook, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibm.com/design/thinking/page/framework/principles/diverse-empowered-teams&quot;&gt;Diverse Empowered Teams&lt;/a&gt; focused on a Hill, it  is important to fail fast, this process regards failure as a learning opportunity, in order words, fail fast and iterate quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As Thato Rammoko quotes Humans never fail, We only run out of Time, Scope or Capacity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TSC (Time, Scope and Capacity) school of thought is a large enough argument for another article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;characteristics-of-dysfunctional-teams&quot;&gt;Characteristics of Dysfunctional Teams?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/team-fail-illustration.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Team Fail Illustration&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cohesiveness of a group depends on the total field of forces that act on that group. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://fortune.com/2017/06/15/corporate-skunkworks-innovation-startups-facebook-oracle-walmart/&quot;&gt;Corporate Skunkworks&lt;/a&gt; to Feature Teams etc, being able to identify a point of instability within a team can help towards streamlining objectives and goals amongst members even better. Here are some indicators you can look out for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Autonomy: Autonomy is the degree to which you have control over the means and methods you use to perform your work. Trust plays a role in defining autonomy. Teams lacking in this element are plagued with team members that feel no personal responsibility for the outcome of their work. It’s vital for teams to be bound by common goals and objectives, not by processes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lengthy Conflicts: Establishing a line of action in case of conflict and opening up communication can save a team from breaking up during conflicts.  If we take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindtools.com/pages/article/newLDR_86.htm&quot;&gt;Tuckman’s Team Building Model&lt;/a&gt;, this stage referred to as the storming stage is almost inevitable, as working out a conflict resolution framework early on is beneficial, as most people try to shy away from conflicts. The truth is that at the point of any major breakthrough, the most successful team had to navigate past their storm stage to get to where they are today.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rigidity among roles being played: You observe this as teammates begin to cleave to titles. In a well-oiled team, team members are interdependent on each other, which means that they rely on the individual strengths of other team members, and they all do what’s best for the team. It is vital to highlight that during team formation, team members gradually take on roles that are not just best for them individually but that is best for the team as a whole. In this way, everyone gravitates toward productive positions, and no one feels left out.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Low level of commitment: As described with autonomy, this means sacrifice. For the benefits of the team, team members would sacrifice time and opportunity. High levels of commitment are essential to firmly coupled team. A decline in this activity is a clear warning sign.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lack of communication: It may take some time to gain effective communication, in music bands the leading artist usually uses a few hand gestures to tell her instrumentalists when a cue is changing and these happen without anyone in the audience being able to tell the difference&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lack of Trust and Mutual confidence: Larson and Lafasto have stated that Trust hangs four key principles: Honesty, Openness, Consistency and Respect.  Trust is less a cause than an effect of an effective team. You can’t force the members of a team to trust each other. You can’t set a goal of “Trust your teammates.” But once project members commit to a common vision and start to identify with the team, they learn to be accountable and to hold each other accountable. When team members see that other team members truly have the team’s interests at heart—and realize that they have a track record of being honest, open, consistent, and respectful with each other — trust will arise from that.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are a few indicators among others, just as team structures are sometimes chosen for the wrong reasons, team members are often chosen for the wrong reasons. This brings to attention the need for developing a team formation structure focused on optimal output. &lt;em&gt;Structuring teams for optimal output are at the core of the Result Driven Team Methodology&lt;/em&gt;. A group of individuals who are driven by a common goal and vision and are invested in the goals and objectives of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’ve found these insights to have a wide range of applications, they are just the tip of the team management iceberg. Like all of us, I’m still learning, and I’m curious — Why do you think teams fail? What are the indicators you’ve come to associate with dysfunctional teams? Please, share them in the comments and help us all build better and stronger teams.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="teams" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Most team problems arise from a lack in MOI, which stands for Motivation, Organization and Information, evidence from retrogressive teams prove that the lack of initial motivation and drive, or a clear sense of hierachy</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
