<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/thinking/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2019-10-30T00:12:36+00:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/thinking/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Andrew Miracle | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>I am  a Product Designer and Business Strategist, My expertise is compassed from my long years of experience in software development, data analysis and technical team management for my consulting company TECMIE. These days, I live more freely, enjoy good music and contribute to growth of other software developers through platforms like codingcoach_ and other notable slack developer commnities, I founded TETA and current nate about data analytic and how it drives consumer growth, I am also keen on strong workplace ethics and company culture, because I understand that is what drive enterprise organizations and keep them where they are.</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Your Manager wants you to succeed</title>
      <link href="/posts/manager-wants-your-success" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Your Manager wants you to succeed" />
      <published>2019-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/manager-wants-your-success</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/manager-wants-your-success">&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Your manager wants you to succeed that's the hard truth&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are wired to work, it’s our nature, to glorify God as we cultivate blessing from the created order and contribute value to others through the labor of our minds, hearts, and hands. For most of us this work greets us each Monday morning with a myriad of thorns and thistles. Sometimes we may struggle with our work or with our Managers, Head of Departments, Leaders etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the amount of pressure and expectation in our modern workplaces today, it could be hard to agree that your manager wants you to succeed. Sometimes they may not have the best way of showing it, however, you completing a task helps the company hit some KPI, meet their target and that means results, the type that can help the company’s decision making process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for someone who finds themselves under this form of management or leadership its very important that you should be able to :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-your-work-without-drama&quot;&gt;Do your work without drama&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No body likes to shout or talk too much, if you are given a task, get head on with it and clear it off with less drama and clutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;avoid-giving-excuses&quot;&gt;Avoid giving excuses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This accompanies the drama rule, don’t be or act like an incompetent or relegate yourself to the company liability list, don’t be a farm of excuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ask-questions-when-confused&quot;&gt;Ask questions when confused&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not the stupid ones of course, It is however beneficial to be able to communicate your confusion in a clear and concise manner, upper management staff usually don’t have a lot of time on their hands, so these fellows tend to appreciate concise and straight to the point approaches. It also goes to say that, If you’re having difficulties let them know before hand, however, this is not a license to be giving excuses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remember-the-pareto-principle&quot;&gt;Remember the Pareto Principle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You remember the 80/20 rule, yeah of course, this time around in the workplace you want to be among the 20% that’s responsible for 80% of the companies output, these output means result that’s helping your organization hit a target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More importantly be good at what you do. The truth is that your success is theirs too.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am aware that there could be edge cases where you could be dealing with a difficult manager or boss, if you do find yourself in such situation here’s a simple prayer, where I always find encouragement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lord Jesus, you know I am having a hard time loving that person at work. Their insensitive words and actions are so wounding and hurtful. I really want to avoid them and at times I want to retaliate against them. Lord, guard my heart from bitterness and resentment. Empower me to look for ways to bless them, to overcome evil with good, and to seek their flourishing. (Romans 12:17–19)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="thinking" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">We are wired to work, it's our nature, to glorify God as we cultivate blessing from the created order and contribute value to others through the labor of our minds, hearts, and hands.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Traditions and Cultures we learnt from our Forefathers</title>
      <link href="/posts/fetishes-our-forefathers-practiced" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Traditions and Cultures we learnt from our Forefathers" />
      <published>2019-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/fetishes-our-forefathers-practiced</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/fetishes-our-forefathers-practiced">&lt;p&gt;While growing up in the village, I observed that when elders gather, they always “litter” a portion of wine on the ground, making some incantations which include asking dead men to protect them! Of course the ancestors do not wake up and drink the palm wine. But “wasting” that palm wine is extremely important for a lot of reasons, one of which is safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One key thing I observed was that when the wine is poured on the ground, some elders check if ants congregate towards the wine. If ants do come towards the “littered” wine, it means the wine is not poisoned and safe for drinking. However if the wine is poured and ants do not come around, or either run away – That wine may not safe for drinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking a walk through the evening as you would expect on a Sunday through the streets of Lagos, you wouldn’t help but be amused at how young adults and teens pour libations with Star, Gulder, Orijin etc on cemented floors, when technically the packaging has reduced the possibility of poisoning, and African ants are not consumers of chemicalized beers! :D . Traditionally, on safety frameworks, there is no reason for that. But most people imitate without knowing the basis of the pouring. Yes, you can pray with your &lt;strong&gt;'’foreign’‘&lt;/strong&gt; beer without a need to waste any portion of it, now you can say your prayer with knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not imitate the old without full knowledge of the intentions and consequences.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="thinking" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">While growing up in the village, I observed that when elders gather, they always “litter” a portion of wine on the ground</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Boiled Plaintain</title>
      <link href="/posts/boiled-plantain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boiled Plaintain" />
      <published>2019-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/posts/boiled-plantain</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/posts/boiled-plantain">&lt;p&gt;Not so early this morning I had breakfast, not the usual kind but before we get to that let’s talk about the period before this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had harvested a bunch of plantain from the farm few days ago, unripe as they were, some had begun to get ripe, and today we had only one ripe plantain from the fold, my junior sister favour, the amazing chef at &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.facebook.com/besoma-kitchen&quot;&gt;Besoma Kitchen&lt;/a&gt; had decided she was going to preserve it till later today to make some Fri-ta-tas, while I hungry as I was this morning, saw the plantain as an opportunity to make a really nice breakfast combo of white rice, some boiled plaintain and vegetable sauce; not knowing about favour’s intention, I quickly did as my imagination had pieced together for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut the plantain and made my combo; favour coming into the kitchen seeing my actions, then screamed and said oooohhh I should have hidden it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes of course she should have, just like every entrepreneur should patent their idea, register their company and probably not wait for that time they think is best to initialize and start building their product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never wait because some hungry fellow from anywhere in the world or your brother could come in and do something with the idea, raw material, available opportunity you had and solve a similar problem be it (breakfast, lunch or dinner); the world is alway better without hunger :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So trust me you are better off starting now, and I mean right now, go back to that Kanban board or whatever and push that card to the in-progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lest I forget to mention, I ended up sharing my combo with favour.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="thinking" />
      
        <category term="journal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Not so early this morning I had breakfast, not the usual kind but before we get to that let’s talk about the period before this.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
